J. Michael Brown

Beaverton, OR 97007

Phone: (503) 702-8810 | Email: jmichaelbrown8@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmichaelbrown/ | GitHub: https://github.com/jmichaelbrown/ | Gi

Portfolio: https://jmichaelbrown8.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Expert agilist, with 5 years of front end web development experience and 10 years of software industry experience, looking to transition back into technical development work as a full stack developer. Enthusiastic about teaching, mentoring, coaching, and continuing to learn along with a close-knit team. Passionate about simplifying the complex and using data to inform decisions.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, MySQL

Libraries and Frameworks: Node.js, React, Bootstrap, jQuery, Express

Applications: Amazon Web Services (S3, Route53, Cloudfront, Lambda, EC2, Cloudformation),

Heroku, GitHub

Projects

Scrum Game | https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8/scrum-game | https://agility.help/scrumgame

- Summary: Drag and drop puzzle for teaching the Scrum framework
- Role: Sole Designer and Front End Engineer
- Technology: React

Grill | https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8/grill | https://jmichaelbrown8.github.io/grill/

- Summary: Recipe and trivia web app, calling the edamam and jservice Web APIs
- Role: Lead Engineer, Product Owner, and Facilitator of team of 5
- Technology: jQuery, Foundation CSS Library

Noted | https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8/noted | https://noted-express.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Note-taking web app
- Role: Sole Back End Engineer
- Technology: Node, Express, and deployed with Heroku.

Experience

Nike, Inc. Beaverton, OR Sr. Scrum Master 2020 – Present

- Coach software teams to be autonomous and facilitating their own Scrum ceremonies, resulting in greater sense of ownership and connectedness with the organization
- Facilitate team of teams sync, feature intake, and planning for 7 web front end, native app, and back end software teams as a SAFe RTE
- Advocate for developer community by speaking at engineering forum and coaching community meetup facilitators to create compelling content and drive engagement

Scrum Master 2017 - 2019

Coached agility and continuous improvement for commerce in the cloud software teams

- Created games to teach Scrum framework and software diagrams, resulting in better understanding of the purpose of each sprint event
- Wrote Python Lambdas to collect and summarize team JIRA data to S3, resulting in 90% improvement in data collection and analysis time
- Created dashboards with React to visualize agility metrics and project burndowns
- Led community of practice meetups to share and develop agile and software engineering skills

Scrum Master (Contractor)

2016 - 2017

- Facilitated Scrum Ceremonies for Architecture and Core Components teams
- Created a Node EC2 app to log Hystrix events to Splunk, deployed with automated pipeline

Eleven Wireless Software Engineer Portland, OR

2014 - 2016

- Maintained RESTful C# web services and updated SQL stored procedures for a network administration back end
- Set up Route53 entries and Cloudfront distributions for hosting customer websites
- Designed and implemented a custom content delivery network to push network access portals directly to cruise ships, resulting in a 20x improvement in page load times

Web Developer 2013 - 2014

- Added multiple language support and mobile-responsive design to an in-house Content Management System
- Designed and built simple interfaces for complex network management tools
- Refactored server-side admin interfaces into responsive client-side apps with Angular JS, resulting in better user experiences

Jr. Web Developer

2012 - 2013

- Customized web pages with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery for branded hotel internet access portals
- Created brand templates for non-developers to easily customize portals, allowing entire professional services team to deliver branded templates and freeing up engineering time
- Built a Python script to automate portal deployment that integrated with S3 and MaxCDN

Education and Certificates

Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington (expected 4/2022) ICAgile Certified Professional: Agile Team Facilitation, Agile Coaching, Coaching Agile Transition, Agility in the Enterprise: ICAgile

Fundamentals of Computer Science Certificate: edX/MITx

Certified ScrumMaster and Certified Scrum Product Owner: Scrum Alliance

B.A. Interdisciplinary Computing and the Arts, Music: University of California, San Diego